510-926-7455

t.hoelzer@berkeley.edu

SUMMARY

I worked as a Technical Product Manager and as a Management Consultant

I program in C++, Matlab, python, SQL and Excel VBA. I built a pattern recognizing doorlock with the arduino platform.

I am about to finish my MSc. in Physics and have a background in Economics.

I give talks about Quantum Computing, was broadcasted on national television and 50'000 people watched my video on youtube.

I am a Slam Poet and I like running, hiking and swimming.

EXPERIENCE

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, CA, USA

Visiting Student Researcher

October 2015 - April 2016

- Research on NV centers in diamond with high performance pulsed Nd-YAG lasers
- PROMOS scholar of the DAAD (German Academic Exchange Service)

So1 GmbH Berlin, Germany

Junior - Business Development- / Technical Product Manager (as a freelance Consultant)

April 2015 - September 2015

- So1 GmbH develops new marketing channels using big data artificial intelligence and machine learning algorithms
- Project 1: Internationalization; Market analysis of France, UK, Poland, Italy; Development of entry strategies
- Project 2: Technical Product Management across C-Level, Engineering, Marketing and Business Development; Design and prioritization of product requirements; Monitoring and delivery of 5 new product features for our clients

Glotzbach Hoelzer Schwarz GbR

Aachen, Germany

Management Consultant (freelance)

December 2014 - February 2015

- Self-employed project work as a management consultant to the Chief Financial Officer (CFO) of a local mid-sized industrial auxiliary equipment manufacturer
- Creation of a Key Performance Indicator (KPI) Dashboard for the CFO based on Excel VBA
- Process Design, Coordination and Implementation of 36 KPI's across 6 departments into a weekly updated Dashboard

EDUCATION

RWTH AACHEN UNIVERSITY

Aachen, NRW, Germany

MSc. Physics

October 2013 - April 2016

- Academics: Specialization on Theoretical Quantum Computing with Electron Spin Qubits in Silicon
- Honors: Member of the MLP Excellence Finalist Network, Contact Network with Partners from Economics and Science
- Extracurricular: First-Year-Students-Tutor, International-Students-Tutor

RWTH AACHEN UNIVERSITY

Aachen, NRW, Germany

MSc. Economics - General Management

October 2013 - July 2017

Academics: Courses in Risk Management, Operations Research, Decision Theory, Statistics, Negotiations

DELFT UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Delft, South Holland, Netherlands

MSc. Physics

February 2014 - September 2014

- Academics: Semester Abroad, Specialization on Theoretical Quantum Computing with Electron Spin Qubits in Silicon
- Honors: ERASMUS scholar (European Region Action Scheme for the Mobility of University Students)

RWTH AACHEN UNIVERSITY

Aachen, NRW, Germany

BSc. Physics

October 2011 - September 2013

- Academics: German GPA 1.9. Specialization on Theoretical Quantum Computing Error Correction.
- Honors: Scholar of the German Physical Association (for extraordinary performance in Physics)
- Extracurricular: Google+ Community Manager, Support for student associations and teachers regarding public relations